<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>HCI, GameDev on Alisa Kobzar</title>
    <link>https://alisakobzar.github.io/gamedev/</link>
    <description>Recent content in HCI, GameDev on Alisa Kobzar</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alisakobzar.github.io/gamedev/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Avatara</title>
      <link>https://alisakobzar.github.io/gamedev/avatara/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisakobzar.github.io/gamedev/avatara/</guid>
      <description>short opera by Christof Ressi for 2 singers, 2 VR performers, ensemble, live video and live electronics
role: VR game developer, HCI-designer, motion tracking technician</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Excerpt from the Earth diary</title>
      <link>https://alisakobzar.github.io/gamedev/earthdiary/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisakobzar.github.io/gamedev/earthdiary/</guid>
      <description>For clarinet and electronics.
First prototype of interactive 3D sonic object, inspired by the model-based sonification and powered with the generative grammars algorithmic composition method and by the logic of game-design.
Performer: Dmytro Pashynskyi (Clarinet)
Created within the project Pandemic media space
a short interview
excerpts from the Prototype and Encapsulated Chapters:
Mozilla Hubs Encapsulated chapters</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Springing</title>
      <link>https://alisakobzar.github.io/gamedev/springing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisakobzar.github.io/gamedev/springing/</guid>
      <description>Game-assisted live-electronics composition
„Springing“ is a piece for one computer music performer and a stereo output. The initial idea was springs with which you can interact without hearing the acoustic result of that interaction except a synthesised one. This spring should be treated metaphorically as a magnetic tape from the old analog tape machines with the writing and reading heads. This invisible spring should exist within the constraints of a virtual physics system (implemented within the Unity game engine ) and be accessible for interaction with the help of the Optitrack motion capture system (version 2) or NanoKontrol interface (version 1) .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do_You_Hear_Me?</title>
      <link>https://alisakobzar.github.io/gamedev/do_you_hear_me/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisakobzar.github.io/gamedev/do_you_hear_me/</guid>
      <description>Game prototype. Protagonist: Maria Kalesnikawa (contemporary flautist, imprisoned Belorussian activist), who goes in a night dream (nightmare - achieved with the help of various visual glitches, which confuse the player&amp;rsquo;s navigation) through the stages of her life (labyrinth ) in reverse from now until the point, when she decided, that the political future of her country is more important than her successful musical career. The goal of the game is to find the protagonist&amp;rsquo;s lost voice.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
