<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Duo rotkäppchen on Alisa Kobzar</title>
    <link>https://alisakobzar.github.io/duo-rotkaeppchen/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Duo rotkäppchen on Alisa Kobzar</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alisakobzar.github.io/duo-rotkaeppchen/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>_rotkaeppchen CV (EN)</title>
      <link>https://alisakobzar.github.io/duo-rotkaeppchen/1_rotkaeppchen-cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisakobzar.github.io/duo-rotkaeppchen/1_rotkaeppchen-cv/</guid>
      <description>rotkäppchen duo is an Austria-based collaboration between the composer and multimedia artist Alisa Kobzar and the dancer and choreographer Lisa Mc Guire. Since 2019 they are creating art projects together and performing in Vienna, Graz, Salzburg, Oslo as well as via live stream to Hong Kong. rotkäppchen has been part of concerts (Institute of Electronic Music and Acoustics concerts, Kunsthaus Graz), multimedia exhibitions (Pointlessness), conferences (Audio Mostly, DACA) and also produced their own performances (TIK, Sargfabrik, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>_rotkaeppchen-photos</title>
      <link>https://alisakobzar.github.io/duo-rotkaeppchen/2_rotkaeppchen-photos/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisakobzar.github.io/duo-rotkaeppchen/2_rotkaeppchen-photos/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>crossproduct</title>
      <link>https://alisakobzar.github.io/duo-rotkaeppchen/crossproduct/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisakobzar.github.io/duo-rotkaeppchen/crossproduct/</guid>
      <description>Dance on screen project.
​&amp;quot;Cross product&amp;quot; is a short film, that combines visual art, music and dance into one inseparable media. The main idea of the movie is based on the algebraic definition, that says: “The Cross Product a × b of two vectors is another vector that is at right angles to both.&amp;quot;
Read more
Sound, visuals - Alisa Kobzar
Choreography, dance - Lisa Mc Guire</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Floating pointers (ver. A, B, C)</title>
      <link>https://alisakobzar.github.io/duo-rotkaeppchen/floatingpointersabc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisakobzar.github.io/duo-rotkaeppchen/floatingpointersabc/</guid>
      <description>The „Floating pointers“ project exists in 4 versions, 3 of which have been already presented in different venues in Salzburg (A), Graz (B), and Eckernförde (C) (Provinzlärm Festival).
Version A explores the human-computer interaction methods with the dancer’s complete control of the sound medium, version B is focused on the human-to-human interaction as an alternative interpretation of the same computer music instruments. Version C combines both approaches and invites the audience to compare the beautiful and completely different results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Floating pointers (ver.D)</title>
      <link>https://alisakobzar.github.io/duo-rotkaeppchen/floatingpointersd/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisakobzar.github.io/duo-rotkaeppchen/floatingpointersd/</guid>
      <description>The „Floating pointers“ project exists in 4 versions, 3 of which have been already presented in different venues in Salzburg (A), Graz (B), and Eckernförde (C) (Provinzlärm Festival).
Version A explores the human-computer interaction methods with the dancer’s complete control of the sound medium, version B is focused on the human-to-human interaction as an alternative interpretation of the same computer music instruments. Version C combines both approaches and invites the audience to compare the beautiful and completely different results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>grow</title>
      <link>https://alisakobzar.github.io/duo-rotkaeppchen/grow/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisakobzar.github.io/duo-rotkaeppchen/grow/</guid>
      <description>“Grow” combines dance in the limited space of the beamer’s projection with the visual art, operated in real time, and live electronic music, synthesised and played live.
The piece explores the transformative relationships between the body and technology. The reaction-interactions chains between the dancer and composer/multimedia artist are the result of nonverbal communication. Visually the role of the dancer is to propose the movement sequences, which receive immediate reactions in music and/or visual content because of the active visual following, or vice versa - the dancer reacts on the sound sequence, proposed by the composer in real time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>the room of the lost memories</title>
      <link>https://alisakobzar.github.io/duo-rotkaeppchen/theroomofthelostmemories/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisakobzar.github.io/duo-rotkaeppchen/theroomofthelostmemories/</guid>
      <description>Live performance with the active motion-tracking system, where the dancer interacts with the invisible objects and fully controls the sound.
Flashback into the space, where everything is questionably existing in the personal emotional relations with the memory-carrier. The memories come and go not always as expected, forcing the carrier to live them shortly again. There is no evidence how the memories are connected. The reality after flashback is not perceived in the same way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>before the first flight</title>
      <link>https://alisakobzar.github.io/duo-rotkaeppchen/beforethefirstflight/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisakobzar.github.io/duo-rotkaeppchen/beforethefirstflight/</guid>
      <description>Motion capture, character design, sound, video - Alisa Kobzar
Dance - Lisa Mc Guire
This project explores the beauty of the sensors&amp;rsquo; noise, introduced by the Optitrack system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a letter to humboldt</title>
      <link>https://alisakobzar.github.io/duo-rotkaeppchen/humboldt/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisakobzar.github.io/duo-rotkaeppchen/humboldt/</guid>
      <description>Live electronic music, live visual art, dance in front of the video projection.
Alexander von Humboldt (1769- 1859) is a german geographer, naturalist, explorer and the first person to describe the phenomenon and cause of human-induced climate change, in 1800 and again in 1831, based on observations generated during his travels. How could he react on the climate changes today? In the piece „a letter to Humboldt“ we want to pay people’s attention to the beauty and at the same time vulnerability of the nature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>grasshoppers</title>
      <link>https://alisakobzar.github.io/duo-rotkaeppchen/grasshoppers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisakobzar.github.io/duo-rotkaeppchen/grasshoppers/</guid>
      <description>Installation and dance performance with the IKO in Kunsthaus Graz (Open Mic series).
Choreography and concept: Lisa Mc Guire Music: Alisa Kobzar Performers: Johanna Schmied-Schimeczek, Carmen Barbalata, Blessing Emweghere, Valentina Sander
More about the project</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>lebensformen 1a , 1b, 1c</title>
      <link>https://alisakobzar.github.io/duo-rotkaeppchen/lebensformen1a1b1c/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisakobzar.github.io/duo-rotkaeppchen/lebensformen1a1b1c/</guid>
      <description>This project explores the feedback connection between the inner and outer.
Initially planned as a project for 2 dancers and a e-violin performer (version 1), producing an effect on each other during the performance, because of the COVID-19 restrictions project has the live instrumental component. Currently project exists in 4 versions. Version 1 explores the 3 elementary living forms, coexisting and sharing the multimedia and physical spaces. Version 1 (inner) A is connecting the oscillations of one dancer between the inner and outer worlds as seen from the perspective of another dancer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>U92</title>
      <link>https://alisakobzar.github.io/duo-rotkaeppchen/u92/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisakobzar.github.io/duo-rotkaeppchen/u92/</guid>
      <description>Live electronic music , live visual art, dance in front of the video projection.
In the project “U-92” we make an artistic exploration in the field of interactive space with transformational reactions on chemical processes of uranium. Our Society uses this diverse element with good intention (nuclear-medicine) or for demonstrating power (weapons). Another problematic subject is its inexhaustible resource of energy, which we are producing (nuclear reactor) in a careless way.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
